Guide to the Stanford University, School of Education, Undergraduate Honors Program, Theses SC4-2764
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, School of Education, Undergraduate Honors Program, theses
1990-2011
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Graduate School of Education
SC4-2764
2.25 Linear Feet (33 volumes in 5 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University School of Education Undergraduate Honors Program.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University School of Education Undergraduate Honors Program.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Acquisition Information
Theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Education -- Study and teaching; Student papers.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Bangser, Jill V., The ideal vs. actual roles of school psychologists in K-12 public school districts., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Ehrhardt, Britt L., Training peer sexual health educators: changes in trainees' knowledge, self-beliefs and sexual behavior., 2004 (Box 1)
  - Higgins, Scarlett, Desgregation through the courts: delay, denial and disillusionment in the San Francisco Unified School District., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Mann, Kristen, A comparative study of factors affecting language policy discourse in Kenya and Tanzania., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Medeiros, Nicole, Unrecognized struggles: an analysis of Afro-Brazilian mobilization for educational access, 1930-2001., 2006 (Box 1)
  - Ming, Racy, Desegregation in a diverse and competitive environment: admisssions at Lowell High School., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Potter, Stephanie, Challenges in Aboriginal education reform: Cherbourg State School as a case study., 2007 (Box 1)
  - Purnell, Rogéair, Educational excellence, multiculturalism, and self-concept: critical issues for African American education., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Ramarathnam, Smeeta, The political acceptance of Goals 2000 in Texas., undated (Box 1)
  - Saldívar, José Luis, La Maquina: high school football as cultural resistance in an rural south Texas community., 2001 (Box 1)
  - Smith, Courtney Erin, Women's reflections on friendship and socialization in single-sex and coeducational high schools., 2005 (Box 1)
  - Sopko, Anna, Message and medium: perspectives on two-way bilingual immersion., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Margaret M., The teaching of literature: a study of American and British curricula, perspectives, and methods., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Boyce, Suzanne M., Community control in action: the creation of the Zuni public school district., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Brunski, Leah, In search of parent involvement: a look at California charter school parent contracts., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Burian-Fitzgerald, Marisa, External school evaluations and their impact on teachers: case studies in the United States and England., 2000 (Box 2)
  - Liu, Goodwin, Building common ground: tapping the potential of business involvement in science education., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Longoria, Benjamin, Are we overmedicating America's children? Methylphenidate consumption, a twenty year analysis., 2000 (Box 2)
  - Mokoena, Motlatsi, Systems of knowledge: pedagogics and teacher politics in South Africa: the case of teachers' disunity, 1980-1994., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Sanchez, Marianna, The Crosscultural, Language and Academic Development (CLAD) Program: an in-depth look at California's teacher credentialing system., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Teper, Vlada, World literature curricula: foreign text selection in Moscow and California bay area high schools., 2002 (Box 2)
  - Terrazas, Paula, The attitudes of Mexican parents towards their native language: proficiency, maintenance, loss, bilingualism, and schooling., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Torney, Robbie, Consequences, motives, and social justice: public school choice in two philosophical traditions., 2009 (Box 2)
  - Wilhelm, Kelly M., Identifying predictors for promoting professionalism in teaching., 2001 (Box 2)
  - Yiu, Lisa, Teaching goals of eighth grade mathematics teachers: case study of two Japanese public schools., 200 (Box 2)
  - Carreon, Victoria, A call for harmony: reform of social services for migrant children in CA [California]., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Rettig, Christopher J., Teacher perceptions of the Standardized Testing and Reporting Program (STAR)., 2000 (Box 3)
  - Stevens, Amy, Caring and interdependence: school and community, the history of an "alternative" high school., 1994 (Box 3)
  - González, Marisela, "We talk like civilized people here": young interpreters brokering inequality., 2000 (Box 3)
  - Lopez, Alejandra Marcella, Do tracking and school location affect students' access to qualified teachers and students' perceptions of opportunity to learn?., 1995 (Box 3)
  - Blume, Carolyn L., Story, concept, or moral lesson; teachers' perspectives on the Holocaust as history., 1994 (Box 3)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2018-060
  - Uyeshiro, Lauren, "Learning from the bard: the creation and analysis of the TRANSFORM workshop and student initiated course", 2004 May (Box 1)
  - Nader, Cassandra Lynn, "Putting language minority students' reading development into context: new evidence from the ECLS-K", 2011 May (Box 1)